(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
2021/11/28 初配信デビュー！
2021/11/28 First Stream Debut!
初めまして！
Nice to meet you!
せーの、こんこよー！
Ready, set... Konkoyo!
2021/12/03 マヨネーズASMR爆誕
2021/12/03 Mayonnaise ASMR is born
2021/12/22 コラボ解禁日に凸待ち
2021/12/22 Waiting for callers on collab ban lift day
ホロライブ、あったけぇ...
Hololive is so warm...
2021/12/29 JumpKing
12時間耐久＆クリア耐久20時間
12-hour endurance & 20-hour clear endurance
ちょっと、ちょ、あー！
Wait, wai- Ahh!
なんで落ちた！？バカ野郎！
Why did I fall?! You idiot!
2022/01/29 Bus Simulator
歩道を爆走しコメント欄困惑
Roaring down the sidewalk, confusing the chat
走れー！
Run!
2022/03/15 誕生日は5回行動
2022/03/15 Birthday: 5 streams in one day
27名の方に本当にお越しいただきました！
Twenty-seven people actually came!
2022/04/06 ミオ先輩始動により壺おじ初登頂
2022/04/06 First top reached in Getting Over It thanks to Mio-senpai
あー！ミオしゃー！やったー！
Ahh! Mio-sha! I did it!
2022/05/22 上：パワプロ伝説の3-9逆転劇と迷台詞
2022/05/22 Top: Pawapuro's legendary 3-9 comeback and weird lines
打ったー！入ったー！
She hit it! It's in!
逆転サヨナラ満塁ホームラン！
A walk-off grand slam!
すごいよすごいよすごいよ！
Incredible, incredible, incredible!
土美味しいね！
The dirt tastes good!
2022/06/16 3Dお披露目＆初ソロ曲「WAO!!」公開
2022/06/16 3D Debut & First solo song 'WAO!!' release
わーお！
WAO!
2022/08/09 博衣の日に遂に白衣脱衣
2022/08/09 Koyori Day: Finally taking off the white robe
2022/08/23 セカワRTA世界一記録達成（11時間）
2022/08/23 Sekaro RTA: World record achieved (11 hours)
意識どうなってんのよ！
What's wrong with your consciousness?!
2022/09/02 へたっぴマリオシリーズ開始
2022/09/02 'Clumsy Mario' series starts
2022/10/19 初カメラ有り料理配信
2022/10/19 First cooking stream with camera
のー、しゅ、く、は、ぽー！
No, shu, ku, ha, po!
2022/10/24 まさかのOUTLASTクリア
2022/10/24 Unexpectedly clearing OUTLAST
2022/10/27 新髪型でぱっつんお披露目
2022/10/27 New hairstyle: Bangs reveal
前髪！切っちゃった！
My bangs! I cut them!
2022/11/15 朝こよ！100回達成！
2022/11/15 AsaKoyo! 100 episodes reached!
朝こよ祝100回！
AsaKoyo celebrating 100 episodes!
もうキミの心　ずっと　しぇあ
I'll keep sharing your heart forever
わおーん！
Wao-n!
「絶対無理」って思っちゃうし
I think it's "absolutely impossible"
だってだって不安になるし
Because, because I get anxious
全然嘘つけないし
I can't lie at all
だってだってバカ正直だし
Because, because I'm foolishly honest
目指すキラキラもきっと僕次第だ
The sparkle I aim for is surely up to me
ビター？ギブアップ？なんて言わないんだから
Bitter? Give up? I won't say things like that!
じっとしてられないし
I can't stay still
だってだって動いちゃうし
Because, because I keep moving
ワン・ツー・ステップアップ
One, two, step up!
ちょっとずつ進めば夢の四季溶けちゃうの
If I move bit by bit, the seasons of my dreams will melt away
なりたい僕を　君が好きな僕を
The "me" I want to be, the "me" you like
ちゃんと余りなく見せたいの
I want to show it all to you properly
あちゃちゃ　びっくりするほどできないじゃん
Uh-oh, I'm surprisingly bad at this
間違って悩んだりばっかりじゃん
Always making mistakes and worrying
けど君に見つけてほしくて
But I want you to find me
僕は君を迎えに行くんだ　出会えたならハッピー
I'm coming to pick you up, if we meet, it's happy
わーお！　泣いて泣いて愛して　しっぽ振って
WAO! Cry, cry, love, and wag my tail
わーお！　ダメな僕をどうぞ覚えておいて
WAO! Please remember the clumsy me
もうキミの心　ずっと　しぇあ
I'll keep sharing your heart forever
もうどうしようとかたまに思っちゃって沈んだり
Sometimes I wonder what to do and feel down
案外いけるかも　ふわり浮かんじゃって元通り
But maybe I can do it, I float back up to normal
べったりがやめられない　おかわりって何だっけ？
I can't stop being clingy, what was that about a second helping?
うっかりがとめられない　また歩いて棒に当たるの
I can't stop my carelessness, I'm prone to bad luck again
1、1、ステップアップ
1, 1, step up
悩んだふりしてるのやめて　はいこっちおいで
Stop pretending to worry and come over here.
欲しがる君と　あげすぎな僕とで
With you wanting more and me giving too much,
もっといける気がしています
I feel like we can go even further.
びっくりするほどできないじゃん
You're surprisingly incapable,
間違って悩んだりばっかりじゃん
always making mistakes and worrying.
けど君に見つけてほしくて
But I want you to find me,
僕は君を迎えに行くんだ　出会えたならハッピー
so I'm coming to get you. I'm happy if we meet!
だって　やっぱりひとりじゃダメだけど
Because, after all, being alone is no good,
集まって馬鹿してわおっ言えば
but if we gather, act silly, and say "WAO!"
ほらいつでも言える「おかえり」
See, we can always say "Welcome home."
僕は君に伝えたいんだ　大いなるハッピー
I want to bring you a great happiness.
わーおわお叫んじゃえ
WAO WAO, just shout it out!
泣いて騒いで愛して尻尾振って
Cry, fuss, love, and wag your tail.
わーおわお叫んじゃえ
WAO WAO, just shout it out!
ダメな僕をどうか覚えておいて
Please remember my flawed self.
(正解キラキラもっと眩しく) 次第だ
(The answer sparkles more brightly) depending on you!
ビター？ギブアップなんて言わないんだ
Bitter? I'm not going to say I give up.
(加速メラメラぐっと) 次第だ
(Acceleration flaring up) depending on you!
恥ずかずに希望へと大爆走
Running full speed towards hope without being shy.
君の所近く行っちゃって
Going close to where you are...
いいじゃん　ハッピーじゃん
It's fine! It's happy!
はーい！みんな！こんこよー！
Hi everyone! Konkoyo!
ホロライブ6期生、秘密結社holoXの頭脳、博衣こよりだよー！
Hololive 6th gen, the brains of holoX, Hakui Koyori here!
本日、11月28日に博衣こより、1周年を迎えました！やったー！やったー！
Today, on Nov 28th, I've reached my 1st anniversary! Yay! Yay!
うー、ちょっと息切れてますけれども...
Ugh, I'm a bit out of breath, but...
1曲目はですね、DECO*27さんに作っていただきました、こよの初めてのオリジナル曲「WAO!!」お聴きいただきました！
For the first song, you heard my first original song, "WAO!!," by DECO*27!
どうだった？どうだったかなー？あー、コメントもホントにたくさん！盛り上がってもらって、ありがとう！嬉しい！
How was it? So many comments! Thank you for the excitement! I'm so happy!
ハッシュタグは「#博衣こより1周年」でやっておりますので、Twitterでもいっぱい呟いて盛り上げてください！
The hashtag is #HakuiKoyori1stAnniversary, so please tweet a lot and liven things up!
というわけで、今日はこよりらしさを詰め込んだ「THE KOYORI」の1時間を準備しました！
So today, I've prepared a one-hour show called "THE KOYORI," filled with all things Koyo!
最後の最後までお知らせやお披露目がいっぱいあるので、最後まで見ていってください！
There are lots of announcements and reveals until the very end, so please stay tuned!
それじゃあ、次に歌うのは...
Well then, the next song is...
お？え？
Oh? Eh?
あ、何何何何何何！うわああ！怖い！
Ah, what what what what! Uwaaa! Scary!
うわああ！どういうことですか！ラボに戻されてるし、手錠、ついてるんですけど！
Uwaaa! What's going on! I'm back in the lab and... I'm in handcuffs!
え、今日こよ1周年なんですよ！告知もいっぱいあるんで、こんなことしてる場合じゃないんですか！
Wait, today is my 1st anniversary! I have so many announcements, I don't have time for this!
お？へ？なんか出てきた。助手くんと協力して試練を乗り越えろ！
Oh? Huh? Something appeared. "Cooperate with your assistants to overcome the trials!"
助手くんと協力して試練を乗り越えろ！
Cooperate with your assistants to overcome the trials!
え、試練ってどういうことですか？あ、なんかもう1枚ある。もう1枚。
Wait, trials? What does that mean? Oh, there's another one. Another one.
試練、謎を解いて歌声を届けよ。え、何？
Trial: "Solve the mystery and deliver your singing voice." Eh, what?
試練　－謎を解いて歌声を届けよ－
♪〇〇〇を使え
♪〇〇〇になれ
♪♪♪〇〇〇〇
Trial -Solve the mystery and deliver your singing voice-
♪ Use OOO
♪ Become OOO
♪♪♪ OOOO
〇〇〇を使え、〇〇〇になれ、〇〇〇〇... あの最後何にもわかんない。
"Use OOO," "Become OOO," "OOOO..." I can't understand the last part at all.
え、この謎を解いて... あ、わかったこより。頭脳ですからね。曲を3曲歌えば、クリアってことじゃないですか！
Solve this mystery... Ah, Koyo gets it. I'm the brain, after all. If I sing 3 songs, I clear it!
そういうことですよね多分ね。というわけで、じゃあこれから謎を解いて3曲当てようと思います。
That's probably it. So, I'm going to solve the mysteries and guess the 3 songs.
あの助手くん、コメントで一緒に謎解いてください！
Assistants, please help me solve the mysteries in the comments!
ちょっと待ってこれ... なんかエッチじゃない？あ、こんなことしてる場合じゃない！
Wait a minute, this... isn't this a little suggestive? I don't have time for this!
では1曲目、1曲目の謎解きたいと思います。なほにありがとうね。
Now for the first song, I'll solve the first mystery. Thanks, Nahoni.
1曲目の謎、これ、です。わー、何だ？
The first mystery is... this! Whoa, what's this?
あ、あ、簡単なんじゃないのこれ。謎得意なんで。待って。でも...
Ah, isn't this easy? I'm good at mysteries. Wait. But...
ルイ、ぺこら先輩、ぺこら... 名前が出るんじゃないかなって思ったけど、何でこよりは4文字なの？
Lui, Pekora-senpai... I thought names would appear, but why is "Koyori" four characters?
あみだくじで辿っていった先の、出てくる文字でしょ。だから戻ってみよう。1、2...
It's the letters at the end of the lottery lines, right? Let's trace back. 1, 2...
あ、ぺこら先輩の「ら」になったから、ら。
Ah, it ended up at Pekora-senpai's "ra," so "ra."
え、ルイねえの「る」になったから、えーとらる？何？らる？
And it ended up at Lui-nee's "ru," so... "ra-ru"? What? "Raru"?
で、ここからこう行くから、待って博衣こよりは何で4文字なんだ？
And it goes like this from here... wait, why is Hakui Koyori 4 characters?
あ！待って！わ、あ、わかったかも知れない！あ、みんなも書いてくれてる。そうだ！
Ah! Wait! W-ah, I might have got it! Oh, everyone is writing it. That's it!
タカウサギコヨーテじゃ！
It's Taka-Usagi-Koyote!
じゃ、じゃ、みんなのほうが早かったか...
Well, it seems you guys were faster than me...
こよりもさ、コンコヨかな？とかちょっと思ったんだけど
I was thinking, maybe it was 'Konkoyo'?
タカウサギコヨーテってことは、えっと...
But since it's Taka-Usagi-Koyote, let's see...
ぺこら先輩のギウサギのギに１文字目がいったから「ギ」！
The first letter of Pekora-senpai's 'Gi-Usagi' is 'Gi'!
ルイるいがタカだから「タ」にいったから「タ」！
Lui-lui is 'Taka' (Hawk), and that was the second, so 'Ta'!
で、こよりがコヨーテだから３文字目に上がっていったから伸ばし棒！
And I'm 'Koyote'. Since that was the third part, it's a long vowel mark!
「ギターを使え」！どうよ？
'Use the guitar'! How about that?
なんか「オーズを使え」はおかしいやろ。超常現象みたいなの使わなきゃいけないやろ。
Saying 'Use the OOO' would be weird, wouldn't it? It sounds like some supernatural phenomenon.
ギター、イェーイ！じゃ、２曲目！２曲目の謎もください！
Guitar, yay! Okay, the second song! Give me the second riddle!
これがね、これが解けないと推すんですよ、今日。マジでこれが不安だった。はい、くださいください！
If I can't solve this, I'll be stuck here today. I was really worried about this. Please, give it to me!
２問目どうぞ！なに？えっ？！
Second question, go! What? Huh?!
カリウム＋E＋モリブデン＋窒素＋酸素＝？
ああでも、これはちょっとこよりを何だと思っているのか。
Potassium + E + Molybdenum + Nitrogen + Oxygen = ?
Ah, but really, what do they think of me?
このラボを見てね？繋がってるな！研究者ですからね！
Look at this lab, okay? It's all connected! I am a researcher, after all!
これはあれなんじゃないの？あ、待って、なんか後ろに元素表...
Isn't it that? Oh wait, there's a periodic table in the back...
元素表なくても解けるって。周期表か。カリウムは「K」！
I can solve it even without that. The periodic table, right. Potassium is 'K'!
カリウムはKだから、K-E...モリブデン何みんな？MB？MO？
Potassium is K, so K-E... What's Molybdenum, everyone? MB? MO?
MO！窒素はN、酸素はO。これついてきてますかみんな？
MO! Nitrogen is N, Oxygen is O. Are you guys following?
結構コメント欄解けてますね！というわけで...
The comments section is already solving it! So...
K-E-M-O-N-Oだから、KEMONO（ケモノ）！やったー！
K-E-M-O-N-O, so KEMONO! Yay!
来音くんが優しくね、周期表なんて用意してくれてたけど、助手くんたちはもうすぐ分かっちゃいますよ。
Rain-kun was kind enough to prepare a periodic table, but my Assistants figure it out instantly.
こよりも...ま、こより分かってましたけどね！モリブデンMO、分かってましたけどね！
I also... well, I knew it already! I knew Molybdenum was MO!
それでは３問目ください！
Now, the third question, please!
これあり...何なに？タバタバ？タバタバじゃなかった...タバタタ？天才ありがと！
What is this? Taba-taba? No... Taba-tata? Thanks, you genius!
タバタタって何？声に出して言いたくなくなる日本語、タバタタ。え？
What's Taba-tata? It's one of those Japanese words you don't want to say out loud. Huh?
で、試験管に入ってるね。紫、オレンジ、グリーン、赤。緑、赤みたいな。
And it's in test tubes. Purple, orange, green, red. Like green and red.
手錠はあるよ！手錠いま繋がってるからね。ガシャガシャガシャ。音聞こえる？
I have handcuffs! They're on right now. *Clink clink clink*. Can you hear the sound?
え、これ何みんな分かる？タバタタ...日本の東京にある田端なわけじゃない...
Wait, do you guys get this? Taba-tata... It's not like the Tabata in Tokyo...
分からない間、ちょっとセクシーなポーズをして...手錠映るようにしてもらえるといいんじゃないですかね？助手君捉えないで！
While I think, I'll strike a sexy pose... It's good if the handcuffs are in the shot, right? Don't catch me, Assistant!
あっ！みんなちょっと待って、天才じゃん！「飛び立て」。これもう答え言っちゃった！
Ah! Wait a second, you guys are geniuses! 'Tobitate'. I just said the answer!
みんなが解くの早すぎてそのまま答え読んじゃったよ！分かった！解き方分かった！
You solved it so fast that I just read the answer out loud! I get it! I see how it works now!
えっと、これはタ行、バ行、タ行、タ行ってことで...
So, this is the Ta-column, Ba-column, Ta-column, and Ta-column...
で、その「あいうえお」って５個あるから、タの５個目...
And since there are five vowels (a, i, u, e, o), the 5th in the 'Ta' column...
５個目までしか入ってないからね、液体がね。から、タ行の５個目「ト」！
The liquid only goes up to the 5th level. So, the 5th in the 'Ta' column is 'To'!
で、バ行の、これ上から２個目だね「ビ」！
And for the 'Ba' column, this is the 2nd one from the top, so 'Bi'!
で、タ行の１番下「タ」！で、タ行の下から２番目「テ」！
Then the 1st level in the 'Ta' column is 'Ta'! And the 4th level in the 'Ta' column is 'Te'!
「飛び立て」だ！すごいすごいすごい！助手くんごめん、こより解かなかった...
It's 'Tobitate'! Amazing! Sorry Assistants, I didn't solve it myself...
助手くんがさ、答え書いてくれてたから、分かっちゃった。やったー！え、３問解けました？
I saw the answer you wrote and figured it out. Yay! Did we solve all three?
解けた？ピポピポ？やったー！というわけで...
Did we? *Beep beep*! Yay! And so...
お題に該当する歌声を届けよってことだから...
It says to deliver the singing voices that match the themes...
ギターを使う曲、ケモノになる曲、飛び立つ曲を歌えばいいっていいことですね！
So I should sing a song that uses a guitar, a song about being a beast, and a song about taking flight!
やったー！みんなありがと！助手くんさすがこよりの助手くん、助けてくれますね！
Yay! Thank you everyone! My Assistants are the best, you really helped me out!
え、じゃあもうこの３曲歌えば試練クリアできるってこと？なんか試練をクリアしたらなんと...
So if I sing these three songs, I'll clear the trial? And apparently, once I clear them...
あれをお披露目できるみたいですよ、助手くん！じゃあ...
I'll be able to reveal 'that', Assistants! Now...
あ！待って！手錠も外れた！外れたよ！
Ah! Wait! The handcuffs came off too! They're off!
もうちょっと手錠遊びたかったんだけどな。ちょっと時間あるからちょっと付けてください。
I wanted to play with the handcuffs a bit more. Since we have time, please put them back on.
付けられます？いつの間にか取られちゃったからさ。みんな手錠って...
Can you? They were taken off before I knew it. Everyone, handcuffs are...
ここもっと時間かかったらヤバかったんですけど、本来よりも時間が...
It would've been bad if this took more time, but we're ahead of schedule...
負けました。
I lost.
助手くん、マジで不安だったんだよ。
Assistant-kun, I was really worried.
不安だったんだよ。
I was worried.
手錠よかったのに、あ、つけられたかな？つけられましたか？
The handcuffs were fine, oh, were they put on? Were they?
ついたー！やったー！やったぜ！
They're on! Yay! I did it!
これを撮るために今頑張ってたんだ。
I was working hard just to take this.
あ、どう、どうかな、助手くん？
Ah, how, how is it, Assistant-kun?
あ、ちょっと、ちょっと下から煽りとか...
Ah, maybe a little, a little from a low angle...
え、待って、なんかギターある！
Wait, there's a guitar!
今気づいた、今気づいた！ギターあります、ギター！
I just noticed, I just noticed! There's a guitar, a guitar!
おもっ！ありました、ギター！
Heavy! There it is, a guitar!
じゃあこれを使って、歌を歌うってことですね。
So that means I'm going to use this to sing.
これヒントだったってことだ。なるほどなー。
It was a hint. I see.
おも、おもちゃんです、おもちゃんです。
Heavy, it's heavy-chan, heavy-chan.
え、じゃあ何、どういうのがいい？
Well, so what, what's good?
繋がってない... 繋がってる！見て見て！
It's not connected... it is! Look, look!
こんなに細いので繋がってるでしょ。
It's connected with such a thin thing.
ちゃんと繋がってるでしょ。助手くんに捕らわれちゃったー。
It's properly connected. I've been captured by Assistant-kun.
恥ずかしい...
Embarrassing...
どうして助手くん、こよりに手錠なんてつけるの？
Why, Assistant-kun, are you putting handcuffs on Koyori?
ねえ...
Hey...
早くライブしろ？
Hurry up and perform?
はい！
Yes!
さあ、じゃあせっかく曲も分かり...
Well then, since I know the songs...
曲はね、まだみんなには分かってないと思うんだけど、
I don't think everyone knows them yet, but
こよりの頭の中にはこれを歌おうってやつがもう浮かんでるの。
the songs I'm going to sing are already in my head.
その3曲を歌いたいと思います！
I'm going to sing those three songs!
それじゃあ早速、歌いに行くぞ！
Well then, let's go sing right away!
あ、道中でこの手錠は外す！
Ah, I'll take off these handcuffs on the way!
Lost my music
さあライブパート行くよー！
Now, the live part is starting!
みんな一生懸命歌うから聴いてください！
I'll sing my heart out, so please listen!
Lost my music!
星空見上げ
Looking up at the starry sky
私だけのヒカリ教えて
Show me my own light
あなたはいまどこで
Where are you now
誰といるのでしょう？
and with whom are you?
楽しくしてる コト想うと
When I think about you having fun
さみしくなって
I feel lonely
一緒に観たシネマ
The movie we watched together
ひとりきりで流す
I'm playing it all alone
大好きなひとが遠い
The person I love is far away
遠すぎて泣きたくなるの
So far I want to cry
あした目が覚めたら
When I wake up tomorrow
ほら 希望が生まれるかも Good night!
Look, maybe hope will be born. Good night!
I still, I still I love you.
I'm waiting, waiting forever.
とまらないのよ
It doesn't stop
No!
眠りのふちで
On the edge of sleep
ユメがくれる 思い出の One day
A dream gives me a one-day memory
あなたの言葉には
In your words
少しウソがあった
There was a little lie
離さないよと 言っただけで
You only said "I won't let go"
抱きしめたのに
And hugged me...
約束がフワリと
The promise softly
暗い夜に消えた
Vanished into the dark night
大好きなひとよ いつも
The person I love, I'll always
いつまでも探してしまう
Always be looking for you
きっと目が覚めても
Surely even when I wake up
まだ マボロシ感じたい Morning
I want to feel the illusion still. Morning
I lost, I lost, I lost you.
You're making, making my music.
もう癒えないの？ No!
Can I not be healed anymore? No!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！もっともっと声出せるんじゃないのー？
Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi! Hi! Can't you give me even more voice?
いっぱい盛り上がっていってねー！
Have a lot of fun!
大好きなひとが遠い
The person I love is far away
遠すぎて泣きたくなるの
So far I want to cry
あした目が覚めたら
When I wake up tomorrow
ほら 希望が生まれるかも...
Look, maybe hope will be born...
Lost my music
...そんな
...such a...
ほらまた夜が生まれるから Good night!
Look, the night is being born again, so good night!
大好きなひとが遠すぎ
The person I love is too far away,
遠すぎて泣きたくなるの
So far it makes me want to cry.
きっと目が覚めてもまだ
Even when I wake up, I'm sure I'll still...
幻を感じたい Morning
...want to feel the illusion in the morning.
I still, I still I love you!
I'm waiting waiting forever
とまらないのよ
It won't stop.
I still, I still I love you!
I'm waiting waiting forever
また会えるよね
We'll meet again, right?
Yes!
怪物
Monster
素晴らしき世界に今日も乾杯
Cheers once again to this wonderful world.
街に飛び交う笑い声も
Even the laughter echoing through the city...
見て見ぬフリしてるだけの作りもんさ
It's all just a facade, everyone's just pretending not to see.
気が触れそうだ
It's driving me crazy.
クラクラするほどの良い匂いが
A scent so sweet it makes me dizzy...
ツンと刺した鼻の奥
Pierces deep into my nose...
目を覚ます
...and wakes me up.
本能のまま
Following my instincts,
今日は誰の番だ？
Whose turn is it today?
この世界で
In this world,
何ができるのか
What can I do?
僕には何ができるのか
What am I capable of?
ただその真っ黒な目から
Just so that from those pitch-black eyes...
涙溢れ落ちないように
...tears won't overflow.
願う未来に何度でもずっと
I'll keep hanging on tight to the future I wish for...
喰らいつく
...over and over again.
この間違いだらけの
In this world...
世界の中
...full of mistakes,
君には笑ってほしいから
I want you to be able to smile.
もう誰も傷付けない
I won't let anyone get hurt anymore.
強く強くなりたいんだよ
I want to become strong, so strong.
僕が僕でいられるように
So that I can remain myself.
素晴らしき世界は今日も安泰
The wonderful world is peaceful again today.
街に渦巻く悪い話も
Even the bad rumors swirling through the city...
知らない知らないフリして目を逸らした
I looked away, pretending not to know, not to know.
正気の沙汰じゃないな
It's not a sane situation.
真面目に着飾った行進
A march dressed in seriousness,
鳴らす足音が弾む行き先は
The destination where the rhythmic footsteps lead is...
消えない消えない味が染み付いている
A taste that never, never fades is stained in...
裏側の世界
...the world on the other side.
清く正しく生きること
To live purely and justly,
誰も悲しませずに生きること
To live without making anyone sad.
はみ出さず真っ直ぐに生きること
To live straight without straying,
それが間違わないで生きること？
Is that what it means to live without making mistakes?
ありのまま生きることが正義か
Is living as yourself justice?
騙し騙し生きるのは正義か
Or is living by deception justice?
僕の在るべき姿とはなんだ
What is the way I'm supposed to be?
本当の僕は誰何者なんだ
Who am I really?
教えてくれよ
Tell me.
今日も答えのない世界の中で
In this world without answers,
願ってるんだよ 不器用だけれど
I'm still wishing today, clumsy as I am.
いつまでも君とただ笑っていたいから
Because I just want to keep laughing with you forever.
跳ねる心臓が
My pounding heart...
体揺らし叫ぶんだよ
...shakes my body and screams.
今こそ動き出せ
Move out now!
弱い自分を何度でもずっと
I'll keep biting back at my weak self...
喰らいつく
...over and over again.
この間違いだらけの世界の中
In this world full of mistakes,
君には笑ってほしいから
I want you to be able to smile.
もう誰も泣かないよう
So that no one has to cry anymore...
強く強くなりたいんだよ
I want to become strong, so strong,
僕が僕でいられるように
So that I can remain myself.
ただ君を 守る そのために
Just to protect you, for that purpose,
走る 走る 走るんだよ
I run, I run, I'm running!
僕の中の 僕を超える
I'll surpass the "me" inside of me.
鳥の詩
Bird's Poem
消える飛行機雲
We watched the vapor trails...
僕たちは見送った
...fade away.
眩しくて逃げた
It was so bright I ran away,
いつだって弱くて
I was always so weak.
あの日から
Unchanged since...
変わらず
...that day.
いつまでも変わらずに いられなかったこと
The fact that I couldn't stay the same forever
悔しくて
It was so frustrating
指を離す
that I let go of your fingers
あの鳥はまだ うまく飛べないけど
That bird still can't fly well, but
いつかは風を切って知る
someday it will know as it cuts through the wind
届かない場所が まだ遠くにある
The place I can't reach is still far away
願いだけ秘めて 見つめてる
Keeping only my wish hidden, I'm watching
子供たちは 夏の線路 歩く
Children walk along the summer tracks
吹く風に 素足をさらして
Exposing their bare feet to the blowing wind
遠くには 幼かった日々を
In the distance, those childhood days
皆様、こんこよー！
Hello everyone, Kon-Koyo!
博衣こよりでーす！
I'm Hakui Koyori!
ついに1周年ライブ当日！
It's finally the day of my 1st anniversary live!
ドキドキするねー！
I'm so nervous and excited!
全力で届けるから、見ててね！
I'll give it my all, so please watch me!
それじゃあ、ライブスタート！
And now, let the live begin!
はい！ごめんなさい、なんかミュート芸になってしまったみたいで
Wait! Sorry, it seems like I ended up doing a 'mute skit'...
えー、ちょっと今、こんな状態になっちゃってるんですけれども
Uh, well, I'm currently in this state...
今ですね、
Right now,
これで試練を乗り越えられたということで
since I've overcome this trial,
アイドル衣装をお見せできる状態になったので
I'm now in a state where I can show you my idol outfit.
えー、あの方が待っているライブ会場に行って
So, I'm going to the live venue where they are waiting,
アイドル衣装、見せちゃいたいと思います！
and I want to show off my idol outfit!
行くぞー！
Let's go!
曲がりくねった道の先に
At the end of the winding road
待っている幾つもの小さな光
Many small lights are waiting
まだ遠くて見えなくても
Even if they're still too far to see
一歩ずつ ただそれだけを
Step by step, just that
信じてゆこう
Let's keep on believing
WINDING ROAD
作詞・作曲 絢香・小渕健太郎・黒田俊介
Lyrics/Composition: Ayaka, Kentaro Kobuchi, Shunsuke Kuroda
全てを愛せなくても
Even if I can't love everything
ありのままの心で
With a heart that's true
何かをただ一つだけ
Just one thing
愛し続けてる人
Someone who continues to love
その誇らしげな顔には
On that proud face
何も負けないほど大きな
An oversized kindness that loses to nothing
優しさが溢れ出してる
Is overflowing
曲がりくねった道の先に
At the end of the winding road
待っている幾つもの小さな光
Many small lights are waiting
まだ遠くて見えなくても
Even if they're still too far to see
一歩ずつ ただそれだけを
Step by step, just that
信じてゆこう
Let's keep on believing
握り締めた手のひらじゃ
With a clenched palm
何も掴めやしない
You can't grab anything
何にも頼りゃしないと
Without relying on anything...
開いた指の隙間から
Through the gaps between my open fingers...
いつか手にしたままの
Still holding onto what I once gained...
夢や憧れの種が
The seeds of my dreams and aspirations...
僕にだけ気付いて欲しそうに
Seemingly wanting only me to notice them,
明日へと芽吹出してる
they're sprouting towards tomorrow.
逃げ出した昨日より
Rather than the yesterday I fled from,
ぶつかりあった今日にこぼした涙
the tears I shed today after clashing...
立ち止まった自分を連れて
Bringing along the self that came to a halt,
あの日の僕に会いに行こうか
shall I go meet the me from that day?
曲がりくねった道の先に
At the end of the winding road,
幾つもの小さな光
there are many small lights,
まだ遠くて見えなくても
even if they're still far away and invisible.
一歩ずつ　ただそれだけを
Step by step, just that alone...
正しさという狭い出口を
Through the narrow exit called 'correctness',
くぐれない想いが僕を奮い立たせる
feelings that can't pass through rouse me.
振り返ればただ真っ直ぐに
Looking back, stretching out straight,
伸びていた今日までを辿る足跡
footsteps that trace my path up to today.
曲がりくねった道の先に
At the end of the winding road,
夢見てたあの日の僕が
the me who was dreaming that day
待っているから
is waiting for me.
やったー！
We did it!
かなた先輩、フレア先輩、来てくれてありがとうございます！
Kanata-senpai, Flare-senpai, thank you so much for coming!
いえーい！
Yay!
こよりちゃーん！
Koyori-chaaan!
はい！はい！何、何何？
Yes! Yes! What is it?
衣装…なんかぬるぬるしてる。
Your outfit... feels kind of slimy.
あ、ありがとうございます！何キャラ？
Ah, thank you! Wait, what character are you playing?
おめでたーい！めでたい！
Congratulations! It's worth celebrating!
ちょっと、あの、3人揃ったんで、あの…
Since the three of us are together, I wanted to...
「かなりあぜ！」って言いたい、いい？
say "Kanaria-ze!", okay?
お、やっちゃおう、やっちゃおう！
Oh, let's do it, let's do it!
せーの！
One, two...
かなりあぜー！！
Kanaria-ze!!
やったー！やったー！
Yay! We did it!
え、この衣装可愛いね。
Hey, this outfit is so cute.
あ、そう！可愛いでしょ！えへへ、お披露目してきました。
Right? Isn't it cute! Ehehe, I just revealed it.
可愛い！え、ちょっと触っちゃおう。おー、触り心地いいな。
Cute! Hey, let me touch it. Oh, it feels nice.
ちょっ、後ろの尻尾も見たい！
Wait, I want to see the tail in the back too!
見たい、見たい！え、めっちゃ可愛い！ちょっと可愛い、このリボンから生えてるみたいな。
I want to see! Whoa, it's so cute! So cute, it looks like it's growing from this ribbon.
可愛い！後ろ、みんなで見たい、あ、見づらいけど後ろ…
So cute! I want everyone to see the back. Ah, it's hard to see, but the back...
そうなんです、フルカラーなんです！
That's right, it's in full color!
えへへ、色味の組み合わせいいよね。
Ehehe, the color combination is great, isn't it?
え、このさ、曲をさ、あのかなりあで歌いたいなと思った理由とかあったりする？
So, was there a reason why you wanted to sing this song as "Kanaria"?
あ、聞きたい、聞きたい！
Oh, I want to know too!
あの、実はこより、小さい頃からあの、自分のコブクロになってくれる人を探してたんですよ。
Actually, since I was little, I've been looking for people who would be my "Kobukuro".
え？どういうこと？ちょっと待って。
Wait, what? What do you mean?
どういうこと？どういうこと、コブクロを探してた？
What do you mean? You were looking for a Kobukuro?
あの、この曲すごい好きで、あの、コブクロになってくれる人いないと、一人でね全部歌わなきゃいけなくなっちゃうんで。
I love this song so much, but without someone to be my "Kobukuro", I'd have to sing all the parts myself.
意味がわかんない、意味わかんないんだよ。
I don't get it. I really don't get it.
コブク…あ、僕たちがコブクロということ？
Kobu... Oh, so you mean we're your "Kobukuro"?
そう、あの絢香さん、コブクロさん。あ、なるほどね、へー。
Yes, like Ayaka-san and Kobukuro-san. Ah, I see, okay.
コブクロさんということで、じゃあ僕たち二人で組んでいきますかね、これからも、かなりあで。
So as your Kobukuro, the two of us will be working together from now on as "Kanaria".
よろしくお願いします！えへへ、ここでまたかなりあで。
Looking forward to it! Ehehe, here we are as "Kanaria" again.
あ、かなりあで写真撮ろうよ！撮りたい、撮りたい！
Oh, let's take a photo as "Kanaria"! I want to, I want to!
あの、前にこうやって、あの、こっちを背景に撮って撮って。
Let's stand in front like this and take one with this as the background.
いますね。
There she is.
3人で。
With the three of us.
今日、この辺にあの、こよりがいるということでいいんですかね。
So, I guess it's okay to say that Koyori is around here today?
姿を手に入れてな。
Now that you've got your form.
ちょっと待って、私3Dの時に…
Wait a second, when I was in 3D...
いいよ、いるよ。
It's okay, she's here.
いるよ。
She's here.
みんなここにこよりがいるからね。
Everyone, Koyori is right here, after all.
本物の、後で貼ってくださいね。
The real one, please paste it in later.
いやいやちょっと、こよりどうすればいいんだこれ、
Wait, wait, how should Koyori do this?
こうすればいいのか。
Should I do it like this?
いるよ、こよりと3人でね。
She's here, the three of us with Koyori.
取れた？やっと取れた、イエーイ！
Did we get it? Finally got it, yay!
イエーイ！
Yay!
撮れました。
We got it.
はい、ありがとうございます。
Yes, thank you very much.
あ、そうだ、ついでにこよりにね、
Oh, right, by the way, for Koyori...
あ、はい。
Oh, yes.
ダメダメ、そっち行っちゃ。
No, no, don't go that way.
何何何？
What, what, what?
次の司令が来ているんですよ。
The next command has arrived.
司令？まだあるんですか？
Command? There's more?
そう、衣装をもらったからってね、終わりじゃねんだ。
Yeah, just because you got the outfit doesn't mean it's over.
え？
Huh?
終わるわけないだろ、ホロライブ。
There's no way it's ending, this is Hololive.
ということでね、あの、次の場所に行く司令が来ているので、ここに行ってください。
So, a command to go to the next location has arrived, so please go here.
は、え、分かりました。
H-huh? Okay, I understand.
じゃあ私たちはもうお別れです。
Well then, we're off now.
うそ！
No way!
じゃあ楽しんで、またな。
Have fun, see ya.
いくよ。
Here we go.
せーの、バイバーイ！
Ready, bye-bye!
うわーーー！
Whoa---!
司令書に書いてあるところに来たけど、ここは一体どこなんだ。
I came to the place written in the command, but where on earth is this?
なんか寂しい。
It feels a bit lonely.
試練
Trial
恐怖を乗り越えて助手くんを笑顔にしろ
Overcome fear and make your assistants smile.
初めてのバイオハザードVRをプレイすべし
You must play Resident Evil VR for the first time.
いやだ、こよ、バイオハザードめっちゃ好きになったんですけど、
No way... Koyo, I've come to really like Resident Evil, but...
いや、でもVRは多分めっちゃ怖いと思うんです、やってきてなくて。
Well, I think VR will probably be super scary. I haven't done it before.
いや、絶対無理無理無理無理、嫌です嫌です嫌です、無理です！
No, it's absolutely impossible, impossible, impossible... I don't want to, I don't want to, I don't want to, it's impossible!
あーーー！つけられたーーー！
Aaaah! They put them on me---!
ということで、無理やりVRゴーグルをつけられたこよは、
And so, Koyo, having been forced to wear the VR goggles,
みんなを笑顔にするために、試練に挑むことに。
takes on the trial to make everyone smile.
始まりまーす！
It's starting!
うわ、緊張する。
Whoa, I'm nervous.
7の最初、あ、これもしかなて
The beginning of 7... oh, could this be...
ミアの映像、あ、お元気？
Mia's video... oh, you're doing well?
かえって、あなたを大事にしてほしいっていう連絡したくて。
I'm coming home... I wanted to call and say I want you to take care of yourself.
ミアありがとう、何？
Mia, thank you. What?
良いニュース、もう少しで家に帰れることになったの。
Good news, it turns out I'll be home soon.
嘘なんでしょ？
That's a lie, right?
このメッセージをもし見てるなら…
If you're watching this message...
これ今の映像や、あ、ミア！
This is the current footage... oh, Mia!
探さないで。
Don't look for me.
探す、探す、探したくないけど探す、イーサンはそういう男だから、
I'll look, I'll look... I don't want to look, but I'll look. Because Ethan is that kind of man.
こよりは探せないけど多分、怖いから。
Koyori can't look though, probably, because it's scary.
すげえ、生い茂ってる！
Wow, it's so overgrown!
え、すごい、怖い。
Whoa, amazing, scary.
ここはまだ怖くなかったはずなんだよな。
It shouldn't have been scary here yet.
うわ、びっくりした！あ、イーサンの手だ、虫が飛んでんね。
Whoa, that startled me! Oh, it's Ethan's hand. There are bugs flying around.
昔のプレイを思い出しながら、イーサンと一緒にミアを探しに来たこよ。
Remembering her past playthrough, Koyo came with Ethan to find Mia.
今日は時間の都合上、残念ながら全編をお見せできないため、
Unfortunately, due to time constraints, we can't show you the whole thing,
ここからは助手くんにたくさんのこよりニウムをお届けします。
so from here on, we'll be delivering plenty of Koyorinium to the assistants.
やめよう、うわ、暗い、
Let's stop... whoa, it's dark,
暗い、暗い、早く助けてイーサン！
dark, dark... save me quickly, Ethan!
ハイジエンドお前もって助けて！
High-spec PC, you too, save me!
ここ開けらんないんだよね、最初あれ開けらん…
I can't open this part, can't open that at first...
うわ、びっくりした、違う！
Whoa, that startled me! No!
ぎゃー！これは自分の手にびっくりしてる。
Gyaah! I'm startling myself with my own hand.
うわー！下覗き込む、すごい、足すくむ。
Uwaah! Looking down... wow, my legs are shaking.
うわーーー！
Uwaaaaah!
VRやべえ！
VR is crazy!
おわっ！
Ow!
いやー、お前を助けに来たのにどうして、どうして？
Nooo... I came to save you, so why, why?
イーサンガード！怖い、ここじゃなかったっけ？
Ethan guard! Scary... wasn't it here?
私…
I...
うわーーー！
Uwaaaaah!
やめてください！ちょっと待ってハンドガン一個しかない。
Please stop! Wait a second, I only have one handgun.
ミアごめんね、邪魔！
Mia, I'm sorry... move!
最愛のミアとの死闘を繰り広げ、なんとか倒すことができたこよさんだったが…
After a life-or-death struggle with her beloved Mia, Koyo-san managed to defeat her, but...
お前も家族だ。
You're part of the family now.
あ、パパさん！殴られたーーー！
Oh, Papi! He hit me---!
パパさん、おじさん、うわーーー！
Papi, old man, uwaaaaah!
ファミパンもあったっけ？
Was there a Family Punch too?
お前も家族になるんだよ！
You're going to become part of the family!
ファミパンおじさんに捕まってしまったこよさんは…
Koyo-san, who was caught by the Family Punch old man...
どうにかおじさんから逃れようと必死に逃げ惑う。
Desperately wanders around trying to escape from the old man.
イーサン行け行け行け行け、行くぞ！
Ethan, go go go go... let's go!
おい、こっちへ来い、早く出よう！
Hey, come over here, let's get out of here fast!
ついにファミパンおじさんとの勝負に挑むことに。
Finally, it's time for a showdown with the Family Punch old man.
いいか、まずこんなところで一人で何をしてるのか説明しろ。
Listen, first explain what you're doing alone in a place like this.
あ、そんな場合じゃない、お前死ぬぞ、お前死ぬぞ、
Oh, this isn't the time for that! You're gonna die, you're gonna die!
俺が？これは仕事だ、いいか、本当のことを俺の質問に答えろ。
Me? This is my job. Now, tell me the truth in response to my questions.
ちょっと待って、どこから出てくるか見て…
Wait a second, let me see where he comes from...
言っても信じるわけないさ。
Even if you told me, I wouldn't believe it.
どこから出てきた？いや話を聞け！
Where did he come from? No, listen to me!
おい、シャッターを閉めるな！待て、何だ？
Hey, don't close the shutter! Wait, what's this?
あ、後ろ、パパさん！
Oh, behind you! Papi!
まて、離せ！
Wait, let go!
うわー！
Uwaah!
行け、おじさん！
Go, Uncle!
うわー！
Uwaah!
やったぜ、おい！
I did it, hey!
おじさん、行け！
Uncle, go!
やった、やったぞ、やったぞ！
I did it, I did it, I did it!
ここまでやれば大丈夫じゃね？
It should be fine after all this, right?
どう？
How's that?
うわ！え、嘘、上にいんの？
Whoa! Wait, no way, you're on top?
上にいんの？上にいる！やめて！
You're on top? You're on top! Stop it!
いい車持ってんじゃないか。
You got a nice car there.
うわー！それおじさんの車！
Uwaah! That's your car, Uncle!
すごい！触れる！
Amazing! I can touch it!
あ、触れ... 触れてるような触れてないような...
Ah, I can... It feels like I'm touching it, but maybe not...
あー、おじさん！おじさん！
Ah, Uncle! Uncle!
もう終わりにしよう、俺たちで。
Let's end this, between us.
おい、何しやがる！
Hey, what are you doing!
やめろ！
Stop it!
やめろー！
やめろー！痛いー！
Stop it! It hurts!
あ、やった。
Oh, I did it.
おじさん？
Uncle?
おじさん起き上がるよ。
Uncle's getting back up.
あー、おじさん！
Ah, Uncle!
おい、お前、どうしてくれてんだよ、このクソ野郎めが！
Hey you, what the hell have you done, you piece of shit!
うそ、うそ。
No way, no way.
燃えてる！うわー！
He's on fire! Uwaah!
おじさん一時期やったと思ったが...
I thought I got him for a moment, but...
これなら、これならもう大丈夫やろ。
Surely, surely it's fine now.
おじさんいい顔してんな。
You have a good look on your face, Uncle.
これで助手君も笑顔になってくれたかな。
I hope this put a smile on your faces too, Assistants.
いや、VRやったことあっても怖！
Man, even if you've played VR before, it's scary!
やったよ、助手君ー！
I did it, Assistants!
イエーイ！
Yay!
試練クリア！
Trial Clear!
はい！ということでバイオハザード7 VRやらせていただきました！
Yes! And that was Resident Evil 7 VR!
いや、すでにプレイしてたからまだできたけど...
Man, I'd already played it, so I could handle it, but...
これ初プレイだったらダメだ、死んどる。
If this was my first time, I'd be dead for sure.
はい、ということでですね、今はものすごいかいつまんだものだったんですけど...
So, that was just a very condensed version...
どこかで何かしらの形でね、ちょっと長いバージョンも公開しようと思ってるので、
I'm planning to release a longer version somehow at some point,
それもぜひ見てください！
so please look forward to that too!
お、試練をクリアしたので...
Oh, since I cleared the trial...
なんと！
Believe it or not!
ライブ会場でまた別のあの人が待ってるかもしれません！だって。
Someone else might be waiting for me at the live venue! It says.
よし！じゃあ急いで行かなくちゃ！行くよー！
Alright! Then I better hurry over! Here I go!
昔々 そのまた昔...
Once upon a time, long, long ago...
とある貴族の仲良しな兄弟...
There were two siblings from a noble family...
ぎゃーくーしょー！
In-ver-sion!
ちゃんとやれ！
Do it right!
じいやが呼ぶ 席につけ
Butler is calling, take your seats.
よーいどん！
Ready, set, go!
ナイフとフォークで応戦いたしますの
We'll fight back with knives and forks.
だって僕らはブルジョアの
Because we're bourgeois,
立派な立派な貴族様なんですもの
Very fine and noble aristocrats.
ひれ伏せ愚民 君との違いを
Kneel, commoners, and let me show you
ヴァイヴァイスロイ 見せてやるぜ
The difference between us, vice-royally.
まてまて まて勝手にそんな
Wait, wait, don't just go ahead and...
見抜けるようなハッタリかまして
Try to pull a bluff so easy to see through.
はーい はーい はい はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
お兄様の仰せのままに（笑）
Just as my brother commands (lol).
あーむかつくぜ！まーじむかつくぜ！
Ah, I'm so annoyed! Seriously annoyed!
兄に対して生意気な態度
What a cheeky attitude toward your brother!
刻の声 ゴングを鳴らせ
A battle cry, sound the gong,
ケンカ勃発で宣戦布告
A fight breaks out, a declaration of war!
悪戯して 悪魔に致して
Playing pranks, being devilish,
ほらほら 煽ってく Style で
Look, look, it's the style to keep taunting.
大安売り 買っちゃったな
A bargain sale, you've bought into it,
毎度ありがとうで君の負け！
Thank you as always, and you lose!
拙い引き出しと 煽りあいの駆け引きで決める
Settling it with poor tactics and taunting bargains.
兄の威厳 見せつけるため 飴と飴 火花散る
To show my brotherly dignity, treats and treats, sparks fly.
両者の目と目
Between the eyes of both parties.
俺を誰だと思ってる
Who do you think I am?
くらえ！おれさまがルールブック
Take this! I'm the rulebook!
へたれじゃない 勇気ない
I'm not a coward, just lacking courage,
ちょっと勇気が足りないだけ
just lacking a little bit of courage.
さあさあ お手を拝借
Now then, lend me a hand,
当たり前だろ 余裕しゃくしゃく
Naturally, I'm perfectly calm.
生まれながらにしてチート
Born to be a cheat,
やべぇ 煌めく人生がスタート
Whoa, a glittering life begins.
当然です 見てみな遊色（ゆうしょく）はガチ勢
Naturally, look, my colorful personality is hardcore.
ハイ論破！ハイ論破！ハイ論破！
Boom, refuted! Refuted! Refuted!
もらってくぜブイサイン
I'll take that V-sign!
はーい はーい はい はい
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
はなまる よくできました☆
Gold star, you did very well!
あーむかつくぜ！まーじむかつくぜ！
Ah, I'm so annoyed! Seriously annoyed!
僕に向かって減らず口なんざ
Talking back to me like that,
とっておきを君に見舞え
I'll show you my best shot,
報復！制裁！挑発しちゃって
Retaliation! Sanctions! Taunting you!
意地悪して 一枚上手
Being mean, I'm one step ahead,
チャンスはもらってくスタンスで
With a stance of taking every chance.
痛恨ミス！あっちゃっちゃー
A critical mistake! Oh boy,
お生憎（あいにく）様だね君の負け！
Tough luck for you, but you lose!
分かってねーなってやつなんだよ
You just don't get it!
オレ様は別にさぁ
I'm not really...
謝ってほしい
I want an apology.
もう少し感謝してほしい
I want a bit more gratitude.
年上のくせに全然頼りにならない
Even though you're older, you're not reliable at all.
名ばかりだよもう
It's just a title now.
今日から僕が兄ね
From today, I'm the older brother.
はい決定！
Yes, decided!
もううるせー！
Shut up already!
むかつくぜマジむかつくぜ
I'm pissed, seriously pissed.
憎まれ口はお口をチャック
Keep your mouth shut with those insults.
ゴングを鳴らせ
Ring the gong.
次世代エンペラーはこの俺だ
The next-gen emperor is me!
僕だ！
It's me!
いたずらして 悪口にして
Playing pranks, talking trash.
ふらふら煽ってくStyleで
With a wobbling, provocative style.
いただきます いただきます
Thank you for the meal, thank you.
毎度ありがとうございます
Thank you as always.
まさかの引き分け！
An unexpected draw!
みこねぇ様！
Miko-nee-sama!
こよ～
Koyo~!
バイオの恐怖に耐えたことで
By enduring the horror of Resident Evil...
みこねぇ様とお歌い歌うことができました！
...I was able to sing with Miko-nee-sama!
やった～！
We did it!
にゃっはろ～！
Nyahallo~!
こよと3Dで並ぶのは初めてね！
It's the first time lining up with Koyo in 3D!
初めてです！
It's the first time!
しかも、お披露目したばかりのアイドル衣装です！
And in the idol outfits that were just revealed!
かわいい！
Cute!
めっちゃシナジーないですか、色合い
Don't the colors have great synergy?
めっちゃピンクで
So pink!
アイドルっぽい！
Very idol-like!
いいじゃないの！
Isn't it great?!
ありがとうございます、来てくれて！
Thank you for coming!
エリートが登場してやったよ！
The Elite has made an appearance!
エリート、エリート姉様、ありがとうございます！
Elite, Elite-nee-sama, thank you!
姉様とちょっと殴り合いしてみたかったんですよ
I wanted to have a bit of a scrap with you, nee-sama.
え、なんで？
Eh, why?
なんか楽しいかなって思って
I thought it might be fun.
みこのことそんな歯向かおうとしてたの？
Were you trying to defy Miko like that?
違います違います！
No, no!
姉様はエリート、エリート姉様！
You're the Elite, Elite-nee-sama!
そうだよ、唯一褒めてくれるもんね、こよは
That right, you're the only one who praises me, Koyo.
そう、こよ姉様大好きですからね！
Yes, I love you, nee-sama!
ぺろぺろぺろぺろ...
*licking sounds*
やめろやめろｗ
Stop it, stop it lol
じゃあ、ちょっと記念写真とか撮ります？
Then, shall we take some commemorative photos?
いいよいいよ
Sure, sure.
じゃあ、ハートとか？
How about a heart?
姉様、ちゅきちゅき！
Nee-sama, love-love!
やったー！かわいい！
Yay! Cute!
パシャパシャパシャ...
*camera shutter sounds*
はい、ちょっと時間も短いんですけど...
Yes, the time is short, but...
今からこよりラボに帰るんで、姉様よかったら一緒に来ないですか？
I'm going back to the lab now, would you like to come with me, nee-sama?
え、みこも？いいの？
Eh, Miko too? Is it okay?
お菓子とか用意してありますよ
I have snacks prepared.
行く行く！やったー！
I'm going, I'm going! Yay!
お持ち帰りー！
Taking her home!
おらー！
Oraaa!
なんか、蹴られたぁ...
I got kicked...
ただいま！なんか、みこねぇ様蹴ってどっか行っちゃった
I'm back! Somehow, Miko-nee-sama kicked me and went somewhere else.
ということで、ラボに帰ってきましたよ！
So, I'm back in the lab!
アイドル衣装をお披露目しようと思っていたところでは...
I was about to reveal the idol outfit, but...
ちょっとミュートの事故が起きてしまいまして...
...a mute accident happened...
これも生だから、ということで...
...that's live for you...
ごめんなさい。でも見てくれてみんなありがとう！
I'm sorry. But thank you all for watching!
ということで、今からなんと！5つお知らせをさせていただきます！
So, starting now! I have 5 announcements to make!
このお知らせの後にまだ歌いますので、チャンネルはそのままで待っててください！
I'll be singing again after these announcements, so please stay tuned!
最後の曲、絶対聴いてほしいからよろしくお願いします！
I really want you to hear the last song, so please stay!
では、まず1つ目は！博衣こよりからの挑戦状！
First, the first one! A challenge from Hakui Koyori!
博衣こよりからの挑戦状
A challenge from Hakui Koyori
なんとですね、この1周年記念配信全体に謎がちりばめられておりました！
Believe it or not, riddles have been scattered throughout this 1st-anniversary stream!
その謎を解いて、概要欄にあとで追加されますURLのサイトに行き、
Solve the riddles, go to the URL site that will be added to the description later...
答えを入力すると、なんと！限定メッセージ動画をダウンロードすることができます！
...enter the answer, and you can download a limited message video!
答えは8桁の数字。ぜひ謎を解いて、こよのメッセージを受け取ってくださいね！
The answer is an 8-digit number. Please solve the riddle and receive Koyo's message!
ヒントは... いつもと様子が違うあの子が鍵かもしれません。
The hint is... that one who's acting differently than usual might be the key.
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you!
そして2つ目！ご要望の多かった、博衣こよりLINEスタンプを、
And second! The highly requested Hakui Koyori LINE stamps...
この後すぐ、もう出てるかも？発売いたします！
...will be released right after this, or maybe they're out already!
イラストはむーらん先生描きおろし、
The illustrations are newly drawn by Mullan-sensei,
めっちゃかわかつ使いやすいスタンプばかりなので絶対買ってくださいね！
they're all very cute and easy-to-use stamps, so please be sure to buy them!
そして3つ目は！博衣こより1周年記念グッズ発売のお知らせです！
And the third one is! The announcement of the release of Hakui Koyori 1st-anniversary goods!
今回のテーマは、『お出かけセット』！
This time's theme is 'Outing Set'!
1周年のご褒美に、助手くんとお出かけに行ったよという気持ちで作成いたしました！
I created them with the feeling of going on an outing with Joshu-kun as a reward for the 1st anniversary!
まずは、『想い出の1枚』アクリルパネル！
First, the 'One Memory' acrylic panel!
観覧車の中で撮影した写真を飾っているみたいなコンセプトとなっています。
The concept is like displaying a photo taken inside a Ferris wheel.
イラストはももこママ描きおろし！めっちゃ可愛いでしょ？絶対飾ってください！
The illustration is newly drawn by Momoko-mama! Isn't it super cute? Please display it!
そして、こよとお揃いの...
And, matching with Koyo...
契約リングネックレス！
Contract Ring Necklace!
こよの尻尾をイメージしたデザインになっています。
The design is inspired by Koyo's tail.
大きめなのでネックレスとしてもいいし、指輪としてもはめられるし、
It's large, so it works as a necklace
or you can wear it as a ring,
アクリルパネルの前に飾れるように可愛いケースも付けました。よろしくお願いします！
and I included a cute case so you can display it
in front of the acrylic panel. Please check it out!
そして、お出かけに使ってねな、エコバッグー！
Next, for when you're out and about, the Eco Bag!
ポイントは、使いやすいデザインとしっかりした生地、
The key features are its practical design,
durable fabric,
そしてめちゃかわな助手君の顔ケースです！
and the super cute Joshu-kun face case!
カラビナがついていて、あの、キーホルダーみたいにカバンにつけることもできますよ！
It comes with a carabiner, so you can attach it
to your bag like a keychain!
さらに！お出かけには欠かせないよねな、ハンドタオル！
Furthermore! Essential for going out,
the Hand Towel!
老若…あ、噛んだ。老若男女関係なく使えるデザイン、
A design suitable for... ah, I stuttered.
A design suitable for all ages and genders,
しっかり水分を吸収してくれる触り心地の良い生地になっています！
made with a soft fabric that absorbs moisture well!
まあね、タオルって汚れちゃうから何枚も持っておきたいですよね。
Well, towels get dirty,
so you'll want to have several.
そして、要望の多かったシステムボイスのセット、ついに販売いたします！
And, the highly requested System Voice set
is finally on sale!
目覚ましボイスやパソコンのオンオフ用ボイス、
It includes 10 types of voices,
like alarm voices, PC on/off voices,
メッセージアプリの通知音など10種類詰まっておりますので、ぜひ使ってください！
and message app notification sounds,
so please give them a try!
さらに、全部セットで買っていただいた方には、
In addition, for those who purchase the full set,
直筆サインと箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカードとASMRボイスをプレゼント！
you'll receive a postcard with a signature
and foil-stamped message, plus an ASMR voice!
ASMRのボイスは、観覧車の中で契約リングをこよがプレゼントした時のシチュエーションになっています。
The ASMR voice is a scenario where Koyo gives you
the contract ring while in a Ferris wheel.
そして、直筆サイン、全員に書きます！
And I'll be hand-signing every single one!
書きます！
I will!
メッセージはですね、あの、こよりは要点を絞れない長文になってしまいますので、箔押しにさせていただきました。
As for the message... Koyori writes long
rambles, so I've made it a foil-stamped one.
ぜひ購入して、「うわ、書く量やばいやばい！」と嬉しい悲鳴をあげさせてください。よろしくお願いします！
Please buy it and make me cry out with joy,
'Whoa, there's so much to write!' Thank you!
そして、4つ目のお知らせ！
And now, the fourth announcement!
4つ目はこの後21時半からメンバー限定アフターパーティーを行います！
The fourth is that we'll be holding a members-only
after-party starting at 21:30!
コメントを拾いつつ、ちょっとね、あの、事故もありましたんで、
I'll be reading comments, and since there was
a bit of an 'accident' earlier,
アイドル衣装をまじまじと見たりとか、
we can take a good look at my idol outfit,
ヘッドセットが実は、あの、こよりオリジナルのものになっておりまして、
and my headset is actually a Koyori original,
見づらいんですけど、はい、こちらをご紹介させていただいたりとか、
it's hard to see, but I'll introduce
that to you,
着たかったけど着るタイミングがなかった水着になんかよくわからないけど着替えたりしますので、
and I'll even be changing into a swimsuit that I
wanted to wear but didn't have the chance to,
期待だけ…はい、ぜひ遊びに来てください！
so look forward to it... yes, please come by!
そして最後、5つ目が重大告知です！
And finally, the fifth is a major announcement!
今から博衣こより2曲目のオリジナル曲を歌って踊っちゃいます！やったー！
I'm going to sing and dance to Hakui Koyori's
second original song right now! Yay!
曲をお作りいただいたのは、七星管弦楽団さん！
The song was created by Nanahoshi Kangengakudan!
恋する研究者というイメージのすごく可愛い曲を仕上げていただきました。
They've finished a very cute song with the
image of a 'researcher in love'.
こちらの曲、配信終了後すぐに全編3Dで撮影した…撮影して収録したMVを公開いたします！
Right after this stream, I'll release the MV for
this song, which was filmed entirely in 3D!
みんなにも踊ってもらいたいキャッチーなダンスなので、3DでダンスMVにしましたよ！ぜひ見てください！
It's got a catchy dance I want you all to dance
to, so I made it a 3D dance MV! Please watch it!
さらに本日24時からは各種サイトにて音源販売されますので、ぜひゲットしておにリピしてください！
The track will be available on various platforms
at midnight, so get it and put it on repeat!
それでは、新曲歌います！
Now, I'll sing my new song!
早着替え、パチーン！
Quick change... Snap!
乙女よ求めよQ.E.D.！！
O maidens, seek it! Q.E.D.!!
Question!!
知りたいな！
I want to know!
君はさ 僕のこと どう思う？
How do you feel about me?
Question!!
僕はね 君のこと
As for me, about you...
あとは宿題！
The rest is homework!
ラブ・ラボ 引きこもっちゃう
Shutting myself away in the Love Lab
何て聞かなきゃって ほら相性(実験中)
I have to ask, look, our chemistry (In progress)
論より証拠主義です
I'm a believer in proof over words
前進あるのみ！
Only moving forward!
ねえ 少し手伝って
Hey, help me out a little
人類の課題
A challenge for humanity
好き×好き×好き×好き×好き×好き＝？
Love × Love × Love × Love × Love × Love = ?
答え合わせしましょ
Let's check the answer
見つけちゃった 魔法の公式
I found it, the magic formula
化学反応 してるよね
A chemical reaction is happening, right?
僕ら
Between us
問題は まだまだまだまだ 未解決(ドヤッ！)
The problem is still unresolved (Smug!)
証明中 恋の予想
Currently proving my theory of love
物理法則 書き足しちゃうもんね(どうだ！)
I'll even add new laws of physics (How's that!)
これぞ天才だ！
This is true genius!
あの子より その子より もっと
More than that girl, or that girl
言って頂戴
Please tell me
乙女よ求めよQ.E.D.！！
O maidens, seek it! Q.E.D.!!
Question!!
やっぱりさ さっきから 僕のこと 見てたよね？
I knew it, you've been looking at me, right?
Question!!
見てない？
You haven't?
じゃあ……僕が君のこと
Then... I've been looking at you
どきまぎ パラドックス
A flustered paradox
慌てちゃって 零れちゃう(葛藤中)
I'm panicking and spilling it (Conflicted)
宇宙も秘密主義じゃん
Even the universe is secretive
ビッグバン！
Big Bang!
ねえ 君とふたり
Hey, the two of us
人類の終わり
The end of humanity
好き×好き×好き×好き×好き×好き＝無限大未来
Love × Love × ... = Infinite Future
答え合わせしましょ
Let's check the answer
魔法の公式
The magic formula,
惹かれ合うたび
every time we're drawn together,
不思議な
a mysterious
レポートは進行中
report is in progress.
まだまだまだまだ未提出
Still, still, still not submitted.
設計中DNA
DNA under design,
君の細胞 書き換えちゃうもんね
I'm going to rewrite your cells.
ズバリ天才だ！
Exactly, a genius!
どの子より
More than any girl,
この子より ずっと
more than this girl, always...
「好き」って言ってるじゃん！
I'm saying "I love you"!
乙女よ求めよ Q.E.D.!!
Seek, maiden, Q.E.D.!!
ねえ、僕らふたり
Hey, the two of us,
人類の終わりに
at the end of humanity,
割り切れなかった あまりだったら
if we were the remainder that couldn't be divided...
ねえ、少し手伝って
Hey, help me a little,
人類の課題
humanity's task.
好き×好き×好き×好き×好き×好き？
Love x Love x Love x Love x Love x Love?
答え合わせしましょ
Let's check our answers.
見つけちゃう 魔法の公式
I'll find it, the magic formula.
化学反応 してるよね 僕ら
We're having a chemical reaction, aren't we?
問題はまだまだまだまだ未解決
The problem is still, still, still unsolved.
証明中 恋の予想
Proving my prediction of love,
物理法則 書き足しちゃうもんね
I'll add to the laws of physics.
これぞ天才だ！
This is a genius!
あの子より
More than that girl,
その子より もっと
more than this girl, even more...
「好き」って言ってちょうだい
Please say "I love you".
乙女よ求めよ Q.E.D.!!
Seek, maiden, Q.E.D.!!
3.14159265358979323846264338327...
9502884197...
Q.E.D.!!
1周年ありがとう！また来年の今日も、一緒にいられますように 2年目も一緒に楽しもうね！
Thank you for the 1st anniversary! May we be together again today next year. Let's enjoy our second year together!
助手くん大好きだよっんーまふっ
Joshu-kun, I love you! *mwah*
みんな、フルライブ見に来てくれてありがとう！そして1周年ありがとうー！
Everyone, thank you for coming to see my full live! And thank you for the 1st anniversary!
いや、めちゃめちゃこのダンス難しいんでドキドキしたー。Q.E.D.スタンプいっぱい使ってくれてありがとねー！
Wow, this dance was super difficult, so my heart was pounding. Thank you for using so many Q.E.D. stamps!
えー、この後面談もありますし、えー、「乙女よ求めよQ.E.D.」の
Uh, there's a meeting after this, and the
MV発表もありますので、それも全部見てください！
MV release for "Otomeyo Motomeyo Q.E.D.", so please watch all of that!
本当に本当にありがとう！2周年、2周年じゃねーわ、2年目もよろしくお願いします！
Thank you so, so much! Please support me in my 2nd anniversary—not 2nd anniversary, my 2nd year!
助手くん、大好きだよっ。んーまふっ！
Joshu-kun, I love you. *mwah*!